<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Network Security | Lucas Müller</title><link>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/tag/network-security/</link><atom:link href="https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/tag/network-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Network Security</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Lucas Müller 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 16:36:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/media/icon_hue97f694b06a8a95b4596fd8a551111a9_7636_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Network Security</title><link>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/tag/network-security/</link></image><item><title>Spoofed Traffic Inference at IXPs: Challenges, Methods and Analysis</title><link>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/publication/2020-journal-ixps-spoofing-muller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 16:36:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/publication/2020-journal-ixps-spoofing-muller/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Spoofer-IX</title><link>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/project/2016-2020-spooferix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 12:40:39 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/project/2016-2020-spooferix/</guid><description>&lt;p>A new methodology to accurately classify spoofed traffic in the inter-domain level using heavily aggregated Internet traffic data, revealing the deep subtleties of scientific assessments of operational Internet infrastructure (2016-2020).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IPE-Analytics</title><link>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/project/2017-2020-ipeanalytics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 13:25:18 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/project/2017-2020-ipeanalytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>The adoption of network monitoring techniques has culminated in a broad availability of raw data. However, giving the large-scale and complexity of long-distance networks and the massive volume of distributed data, minor progress has been achieved regarding the in-depth analysis of this collected data and inferences about the network behavior. This project investigates methods to analyze the data measured by the existing monitoring tools present in the &lt;a href="https://www.rnp.br/en/ipe-network" target="_blank">Brazilian Academic IPÊ backbone network&lt;/a>. The result is a service that provides inferences to aid the process of operation, traffic engineering and network planning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Challenges in Inferring Spoofed Traffic at IXPs</title><link>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/talk/challenges-in-inferring-spoofed-traffic-at-ixps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 15:31:23 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/talk/challenges-in-inferring-spoofed-traffic-at-ixps/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Challenges in Inferring Spoofed Traffic at IXPs</title><link>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/publication/acm-conext-2019-lfmuller/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 19:29:15 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/publication/acm-conext-2019-lfmuller/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Challenges in Inferring Spoofed Traffic at IXPs</title><link>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/talk/challenges-in-inferring-spoofed-traffic-at-ixps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:14:30 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/talk/challenges-in-inferring-spoofed-traffic-at-ixps/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Using IXPs to Measure Improvements of Source Address Validation Filtering in Inter-Domain Traffic</title><link>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/talk/using-ixps-to-measure-improvements-of-source-address-validation-filtering-in-inter-domain-traffic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 11:23:50 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/talk/using-ixps-to-measure-improvements-of-source-address-validation-filtering-in-inter-domain-traffic/</guid><description/></item><item><title>P4Sec</title><link>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/project/2017-2020-p4sec/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 17:18:25 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/project/2017-2020-p4sec/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Project&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Securing Networks in the Programmable Data Plane Era, funded by &lt;a href="https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=1740911" target="_blank">NSF&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.ctic.rnp.br/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/1._us-brasil_collaboration_v3.pdf" target="_blank">RNP/CTIC&lt;/a> (2017-2020).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Context&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent advances in &lt;a href="https://www.opennetworking.org/sdn-definition/" target="_blank">Software Defined Networking (SDN)&lt;/a> have expanded our ability to program the network to its data plane. Through domain specific languages like &lt;a href="https://p4.org/" target="_blank">P4&lt;/a>, network operators can quickly deploy new protocols on forwarding devices, customize their functionality, and develop innovative services. This flexibility comes however with a cost: network-wide security and correctness properties (e.g., isolation, reachability, etc.) become much harder to ensure, because network behavior is now determined by a combination of the control plane-driven configuration and the data plane program that resides on devices (also called switches). Existing network verification tools, which rely on a fixed, invariant model of the data plane, are inadequate for programmable data planes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Goal&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Research new techniques to verify and enforce security properties in data plane networks. The verification techniques we work on extend existing verification tools by automatically generating a data plane model from a P4 program. We also work on adapting existing verification tools to integrate with our dynamically-generated models to verify network configuration updates issued by an SDN controller. We also research novel approaches to ensure that network security properties are satisfied by a network configuration that is based on data plane enforcement. We work to develop an in-line monitor, implemented in the data plane itself, that enforces critical security properties, such as isolation and bandwidth limits, even in the presence of a faulty user data plane program or controller.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Internet Infrastructure Measurement: Trends and Challenges</title><link>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/talk/internet-infrastructure-measurement-trends-and-challenges/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 11:48:07 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/talk/internet-infrastructure-measurement-trends-and-challenges/</guid><description/></item><item><title>SecFuNet</title><link>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/project/2011-2014-secfunet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 16:07:30 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.lucasmuller.com.br/project/2011-2014-secfunet/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Project:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Security for the Future Networks using trusted components, funded by &lt;a href="http://cordis.europa.eu/fp7/home_en.html" target="_blank">FP7&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.cnpq.br/" target="_blank">CNPq&lt;/a> (2011-2014).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Goal:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal of the SecFuNet was to design and develop a coherent security architecture for virtual networks and cloud accesses. The proposed architecture would provide solutions allowing the management of communications security for all machines connected to a public cloud using virtual networks. This architecture should guarantee security in the virtualized infrastructure, through isolation of virtual networks and access control for users and managers, without compromising authorized users' privacy.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>